ABHINAV VYAS

Product Designer (India)

abhinav.uxdesign@gmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/abhinav-n-vyas-258131111/

PROFILE

Product Designer having 1+ Years of Professional and Freelancing experience. Ambitious and always willing to learn, grow and become better everyday. I enjoy conducting user research and designing smooth experiences by using principles of HCI and User Centered Design.

Currently working as Associate UX Designer (Apprenticeship) in a Pune based company in where I am getting an exposure of working in collaboration with teams be them other designers as well as developers, and making design decisions unanimously.

SKILLS

I have a good experience working individually as well as working with a team to brainstrom and whiteboard concepts. I can create wireframes at varying levels of fidelity, and enjoy prototyping ideas. Also, I confidently use the skills I gained during my previous profession of being a Legal Parliamentary Reporter, such as Stenography for notetaking during or after a user interviews to compile and organise the Qualitative Research data.

Softwares that I'm familliar with:

- Figma
- Figjam
- Adobe Photoshop
- Adobe XD
- Slack (for Communication)
- Notion (for Productivity)
- Google Workspace
- · Miro (for Whiteboarding)
- Marvel App
- · Whimsical

Skills as a Product Designer

- Communication & Collaboration
- · Interaction Design
- Wireframing & Sketching
- · Iterative Mindset
- · Prototyping
- User Psychology
- Decent Knowledge of CSS Box Model
- Agility
- Ability to Unlearn
- · Storyboarding & Storytelling

Interests

- Transcendental Meditation
- Mobile Photography
- Psychology
- Travelling & Cooking

EDUCATION

Georgia Institute of Technology via EDx

Aug, 2022 - Present

CS-6750 (Human Computer Interaction) MOOC

My learnings (so far)

- The overall goals of human-computer interaction and the relationship between HCl, user experience design, human factors engineering, and psychology.
- The relevance of HCI to domains like healthcare, education, Fintec Etc.
- The emerging ideas in HCI research, such as context-sensitive computing, gesture-based interaction, and social computing.
- The three main views of user in HCI: the Processor, Predictor, and Participant.
- The feedback cycle in user interaction, including gulfs of execution and evaluation.
- The strengths and limitations of the human user, including sensation and memory.
- The role of design principles and heuristics in user interface design.

Google UX Design via Coursera

July, 2021 - Feb, 2022

- Designed my First Conceptual Movie Ticket Booking Application to help users deal with sudden movie plan drops after paying full ticket amount & introduced a new Payment Checkout feature called "Pay at Box Office" with certain terms and conditions.
- Followed the whole UX Process from conducting user interviews to making pixel perfect High-Fidelity Interface Design for Mobile Devices using 8px Grid System in Figma.

Bachelors of Arts via JNVU, Jodhpur.

July, 2017 - Feb, 2020

WORK EXPERIENCE

Coditas Solutions LLP.

July, 2022 - Present

Associate UX Designer (Apprenticeship)

As an Associate UX Designer (Apprenticeship Trainee), we've been given a responsibility to solve a raw Problem Statement of one of our clients.

- Took the responsibility and started our Teamwork. Collaborated with team members & Stakeholders to Properly and clearly Understand the problem and identified the constraints. Quickly started with Market Research, UX Research & User Research.
- Conducted User Surveys & Recruited Participants for Face-to-Face User Interviews to get Quantitative & Qualitative data by diving deep into the users mind, which further allowed us to make clear design decisions.
- Derived robust data points and analyzed as well as synthesized them.
- Actively contributed to the design sprint & Brainstorming sessions and collaborated alongside with other product designers & team members right from ideation to finalization of the project.
- Tried few ways to brainstorm and ideate & made sure none of our idea gets left out.
- Started out design phase backed by the strong & actionable data derived from our research.
- Made concepts, wireframes, intuitive & aesthetic interfaces keeping in mind the design heuristics & usability aspect of the product by using the power of team collaboration & tested different ideas at an early stage to save time for later.
- Decided on the visual design schemes and elements, made our interactive Components from scratch and Assets for future development, in FIGMA & started to design the app screens.
- learned more about CSS Box Models, Grid Systems and their practical use for properly collaborating with the development team and to fill the communication gap between the designers and developers to a great extent.

Freelance UX Designer

Nov, 2021 - May, 2022

- Consulted a Media Agency to design a QR Code Based Progressive Web Application for a Fine-Dining Restaurant based in our Home Town, allowing guests/customers to view Food Menus and to give Written & Voice feedback. (NDA)
- Worked for a USA Based client as a UX/UI Designer and designed a website for Automotive Industry. Website was about a Product i.e. On-Board Dygnostic System (OBD-II) Scanner for Cars.